Do you know the origin of the word "hard-boiled"?
《小銭形:ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞの語源を
知っているか？
It comes from hard-boiled eggs. Right, the moon tonight looks hard-boiled.
固ゆで卵… そう…➡
今宵の月は まるで ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞだ｡
Why would "hard-boiled" refer to something other than hard-boiled eggs?
なぜ 固ゆで卵の意の ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞが➡
現在のような 意で
使われるようになったか➡
ｿｲﾂは ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣を愛読する
坊やたちが知るには まだ早い｡
It may still be too early for young kids who love JUMP to understand.
ﾋﾞｼﾞﾈｽｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟを 読むようになってから
出直してくるんだな｡
When you grow up and read BUSINESS JUMP, then ask that question again.
[Note: BUSINESS JUMP is JUMP for men in their 20s-30s.]
ただ１つ 言えること…｡
One thing I can say...
それは… こんな ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞな夜は➡
That is...it's on such a hard-boiled night that you feel an irresistible urge to drink.
無性に 酒が欲しくなる｡
Men can only quench their thirst with alcohol.
男には
酒でしか癒やせない 渇きがある》
♪♪(小銭形)｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
I'm a hard-boiled detective... A lone wolf.
[THE HARD-BOILED DETECTIVE]
[HEIJI KOZENIGATA]
[Note: Kozenigata's name is based on Heiji Zenigata, a hero from a Japanese novel.]
♪♪｢一匹狼さ｣
♪♪｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
I'm a hard-boiled detective... Working for an organization does not hinder me.
♪♪｢組織には 縛られない｣
[ACT 1]
[THE AFTERNOON OF THE WOLVES]
(警官)犯人に 告ぐ！
ｷﾐたちは 完全に包囲されている!!
Attention criminal! You're completely surrounded!
(犯人)いや～
もう どうでもいいよ｡
Well, I don't care anymore. Harmony? Class cooperation?
協調性？ ｸﾗｽの輪？
そんな 押しつけの道徳なんて
飽き飽きなんだよ～!!
I get tired of hearing about the morality of such impositions!
疲れたんだよ…｡
死ねばいいんだ 人間なんて…｡
I'm really tired! People should just die!
もう 信じねえぞ！
もう 騙されねえからな!!
I won't trust anyone anymore. I'll never be fooled again.
人間なんぞ
守るより 自然保護だろ～!!
It's more important to conserve nature than protect humans!
どうせ ｵﾚは 大学の入学式で➡
It's a shame that I didn't get invitations from any club on the day of my college entrance ceremony!
[Note: In Japan it is very common for clubs to invite new students on the day of their entrance ceremony. Almost everyone is invited.]
どこの ｻｰｸﾙからも
勧誘 受けなかったよ！
だから どうだっていうんだ！
んなことで➡
But so what? You can't judge a person like that! I can't work anymore!
人間の価値 決まんのかよ！
もう 働きたくねえんだよ～!!
(人質)た… 助けて～!!
(犯人)というわけで➡
H-Help!
So, I'll get involved with as many people as possible,
１人でも
多くのﾔﾂら 巻き添えにして➡
さんざん 迷惑かけて
逃げてやるよ！
stir up trouble and run away! Get ready, you bastards!
覚悟しておけよ ﾃﾒｴら!!
(小銭形)言うことは それだけか!!
(犯人)あぁ～ん!?
Is that all you have to say?!
Huh?
(ﾊｼﾞ)小銭形の ｱﾆｷ！
(小銭形)ここは➡
Boss Kozenigata!
I'll take care of this.
ｵﾚに 任せてもらうぜ｡
(ﾊｼﾞ)ｱﾆｷ!!
Boss!
(小銭形)
組織と規律を 守っていては➡
If you follow an organization and its rules, you can't do something like this.
こういう ﾏﾈは
なかなか できまい｡
Yes, a little tip about being hard-boiled is...to have a little courage and...
そう… ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞのｺﾂは
ちょっとした度胸と…｡
(銃声)
(小銭形)ｷﾞｬｰｯ!!
♪♪｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
I'm a hard-boiled detective... Life is a battle.
[THE HARD-BOILED DETECTIVE]
[HEIJI KOZENIGATA]
♪♪｢生きることは 戦い｣
♪♪｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
I'm a hard-boiled detective... No need to rest.
♪♪｢休息など いらない｣
[ACT 2]
[A WARRIOR'S REST]
《小銭形:ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞに 休息はない｡
There's no rest for the hard-boiled.
In this ruined downtown, there's crime everywhere.
すたれた ﾀﾞｳﾝﾀｳﾝには
犯罪が ｺﾞﾛｺﾞﾛと転がっている｡
だから ｵﾚたち同心は➡
So we hard-boiled detectives keep fighting every day.
日々 戦い続けるのだ…》
(ﾊｼﾞ)ｱﾆｷ 大変です！
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙが ｴｲﾘｱﾝに占領されやした!!
Boss! Something's happened! The terminal's been overrun by aliens.
(ﾊｼﾞ)ｱﾆｷ…？
Boss?!
(小銭形)あぁ ﾑﾘ｡
今日 具合悪いから ﾑﾘ｡
Ah...No... I feel sick today, so I can't. I don't feel like doing anything.
やる気 ない｡ もう 働きたくない｡
I don't want to work anymore. It's like I can't get motivated.
っていうか ﾓﾁﾍﾞｰｼｮﾝ上がんない｡
(ﾊｼﾞ)ｱﾆｷ…｡
Boss...
♪♪｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
[THE HARD-BOILED DETECTIVE]
[HEIJI KOZENIGATA]
I'm a hard-boiled detective... Always faced with danger.
♪♪｢常に 迫る危機｣
♪♪｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
I'm a hard-boiled detective... Constantly risking death.
♪♪｢死とは 隣り合わせ｣
[ACT 3]
[TIME LIMIT]
(ﾊｼﾞ)ｱ… ｱﾆｷ！ 時限爆弾です！
どうしやしょう!?
B-Boss! It's a time bomb! What should we do?!
(小銭形)同心は
常に 死と 隣り合わせだ｡
I'm always putting my life in danger.
But a hard-boiled man like me always gets into pinches like this.
だが ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞともなれば➡
このくらいのﾋﾟﾝﾁなど 日常茶飯事｡
(ﾊｼﾞ)だ… だけど 時間が…!!
(小銭形)わわわ… 落ち着け ﾊｼﾞ!!
B-But the time is...
Ca-Ca-Calm down, Haji.
[Note: Haji's name is based on Hachi (Hachigoro), who is an assistant to Heiji Zenigata.]
(ﾊｼﾞ)そういう ｱﾆｷこそ
手が 震えてやすぜ｡
You're the one who needs to calm down, Boss.
それに しょんべん
ちびってるじゃねえですか～！
Your hands are shaking. And you look like you're peeing in your pants...
(小銭形)ﾌｯ…
それだけじゃねえよ｡
There's more...
胸毛も ﾎﾞｰﾎﾞｰだ!!
...my chest hair is growing!
(爆発音)
(鼻歌)
[THE HARD-BOILED DETECTIVE]
[HEIJI KOZENIGATA]
[ACT 4]
[NIGHT]
(寝息)
(小銭形)ﾏﾏ～｡
Mama...
(寝息)
ﾏﾏ～｡
Mama...
♪♪｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
I'm a hard-boiled detective... A hard-boiled egg.
[THE HARD-BOILED DETECTIVE]
[HEIJI KOZENIGATA]
♪♪｢固ゆで卵だ｣
♪♪｢ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心｣
I'm the hard-boiled detective... Heiji Kozenigata.
♪♪｢小銭形 平次｣
[ACT 5]
[ENDING]
(銀時)おい！
あまり 調子にのるなよ！
Hey, don't get carried away!
You'll be in trouble if you underestimate this TV show.
放送 ﾅﾒると えらいことになるぜ｡
(小銭形)ﾌｯ…｡ おいおい…
ﾔﾎﾞなﾏﾈ するんじゃねえよ｡
Hey, hey, stop being such a stick-in-the-mud.
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞは どんな脅しや圧力にも
屈しやしない｡
A hard-boiled person won't yield to any threats or pressure. That's what...
それが…｡
(銃声)
♪♪～
[END]
No, it's not finished yet. It hasn't even started!
(小銭形)いや！
終わりじゃないからね！
始まっても いないからね！
これ～!!
Shut up! If GinTama doesn't start right now,
うるせえ～!!
いいかげん 『銀魂』 始めねえと➡
今度こそ
本当に 打ち切られんだよ!!
they'll really pull the plug and cancel us this time.
Damn it! Five minutes have already passed!
ﾁｸｼｮｳ！ もう ５分も
経っちまったじゃねえか!!
ﾌｯ｡ それじゃあ ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞｱﾆﾒ
『銀魂』！ 始まるぜ！
Well, the hard-boiled anime, "GinTama," will now begin!
《小銭形:ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞの語源を
知っているか？
Do you know the origin of the word "hard-boiled"?
It comes from hard-boiled eggs. Right, the moon tonight looks hard-boiled.
固ゆで卵… そう…➡
今宵の月は まるで ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞだ｡
Why would "hard-boiled" refer to something other than hard-boiled eggs?
なぜ 固ゆで卵の意の ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞが➡
現在のような 意で
使われるようになったか➡
It may still be too early for young kids who love JUMP to understand.
ｿｲﾂは ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣を愛読する
坊やたちが知るには まだ早い｡
When you grow up and read BUSINESS JUMP, then ask that question again.
ﾋﾞｼﾞﾈｽｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟを読むようになってから
出直してくるんだな｡
One thing I can say... That is...
ただひとつ言えること…｡
それは こんなﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞな夜は
無性に酒が欲しくなる｡
it's on such a hard-boiled night that you feel an irresistible urge to drink.
Men can only quench their thirst with alcohol.
男には 酒でしか癒やせない
渇きがある》
(小銭形)ﾏｽﾀｰ… ｶﾐｭ ﾛｯｸで頼む｡
Master, give me a Camus on the rocks.
[Note: Camus is a brand of Cognac.]
Here you go, Shochu.
[Note: Shochu is a type of alcohol common in Japan and Korea.]
(おもひで酒の親父)へい 焼酎｡
It's not Shochu. You can just call it Camus, Master.
焼酎じゃねえ｡
ｶﾐｭと呼べ ﾏｽﾀｰ｡
ﾏｽﾀｰじゃねえ…
親父と呼べ 旦那｡
Don't call me master. You can just call me Pops, sir.
《そう…
ｵﾚが ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心 小銭形 平次｡
Yes, I'm the hard-boiled detective, Heiji Kozenigata.
今の時代 ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞなﾔﾂには
生きづらい世の中になった》
The current era isn't easy for us hard-boiled people to live in.
[TEL]
ああ… 小銭形だが…｡
Yeah, this is Kozenigata.
なに？ 事件!?
What?! An incident?!
《小銭形:道ゆく者 顔見れば➡
People on the road look like...
どいつもこいつも
火通しの甘い 半熟卵ばかりだ》
That's him. Over there!
...half-boiled eggs.
(同心)狐だ！ 狐火の長五郎だ!!
It's the fox!
It's Chogoro the Foxfire!
(同心たち)あぁっ!?
He ran in that direction. Follow him!
《小銭形:そんなﾔﾂらには
ｵﾚの腰の十手がうなる》
For those guys...
...I use the Jutte at my waist as punishment...
[Note: A Jutte is a specialized weapon used by law enforcement officers during the Edo period.]
よう そんなに慌ててどうした？
Yo, why are you in such a hurry? Are you late for a date?
ﾃﾞｰﾄの時間に送れちまったのかい？
早い男は 嫌われるぜ… 坊やたち｡
Girls don't like men who finish early, boys.
(ﾊｼﾞ)小銭形のｱﾆｷ！
Boss Kozenigata!
If I give them just one big blow, they'll become scrambled eggs.
《小銭形:一発くれてやれば
立派な ｽｸﾗﾝﾌﾞﾙｴｯｸﾞに早変わりだ》
(ﾊｼﾞ)狐です… 狐の面を!!
The fox! It was wearing the mask of a fox!
All right. Even if it costs me my life.
ｵｯｹｰ！ 我が命にかえても！
お前たちは あっちを…｡
You guys go that way, and I'll look this way.
ｵﾚは こっちを捜す｡
(ﾊｼﾞ)はい！
All right!
…うぅっ！
《小銭形:ちと
ｶﾐｭが回りすぎたか…？
It looks like I had a bit too much Camus, huh?
ﾌﾝ… いい気つけだ》
Well, but it may be a good restorative...
Hey, are you all right?
(銀時)おい 大丈夫か？ ｱﾝﾀ｡
(新八)
だいぶ 酔ってるみたいですね｡
You look pretty drunk.
(神楽)吐いたほうがいいｱﾙよ｡
You'd better throw up.
どうすか？ うちの店で
ちょっと休んでいかれたら｡
How about coming to our shop and having a nap?
[Costume Club]
[Monster Fox]
[Nurses, female ninjas... Can change into anything.]
(神楽)かわいい子
いっぱいいるｱﾙよ｡
There're many cute girls in there.
Instead of mice, foxes are finally showing their true colors.
(小銭形)ﾈｽﾞﾐならぬ 狐が➡
ようやく ｼｯﾎﾟを見せたか｡
(３人)ん？
神妙にお縄につけい！ 狐めが！
Surrender quietly fox!
(小銭形)なんていうﾌﾟﾚｲとか
したいんですけど いけますかね？
Can I role-play something like that?
ああ 同心ﾌﾟﾚｲ…
岡っ引きﾌﾟﾚｲもありますよ｡
Ah, it's a detective role-play. We offer undercover-agent role-playing, too!
(小銭形)ﾏｼﾞっすか？
基本 ﾎﾞｸ Ｍなんで➡
Really? Basically, I'm an "M," so I love being treated rough.
結構 きつめに
やってほしいんですけど！
《小銭形:ｵﾚは ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ同心
小銭形 平次》
I'm the hard-boiled detective, Heiji Kozenigata.
["Hard-boiled Egg On a Man's Heart"]
A smoke after work... There's nothing better than this.
《仕事のあとの一服
これが たまらない｡
至福のとき…
もはや これ１本のために➡
It's my happiest moment. It's no exaggeration to say I work hard just for this.
仕事をしているといっていい｡
男は たかが１本のために
命をかける》
Men can bet their lives on just one thing.
What's the deal of sounding like you accomplished something?!
(上司)
何 やり遂げたﾂﾗしてんだぁ？
仕事中に遊んでただけだろうが！
ﾃﾒｴは！
You were playing during work! You bastard!
What the heck are you doing?! What does "one thing" mean?
何してんだ ｵﾒｴ… １本って何？
そっちの１本か？
１本１万円ｺｰｽか!?
Is that the 10,000 yen for one time?!
男には 我慢できない１本がある｡
Men have one thing they can't stand.
(上司)最低なことを
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ調で言うな！
Stop saying awful things with that hard-boiled tone!
あげく 酔っ払って
あんなもん連れてくる始末！
Moreover, you came back drunk and brought them!
狐面って言ったんだよ ｵﾚは！
なんで着ぐるみ!?
I said the mask of the fox. Why did you bring someone wearing a costume?!
どうして いつもいつも…
前から思ってたがな…➡
Why are you always like this?
I always thought there was something uneven between your appearance and working ability!
ｵﾒｴは ﾂﾗと仕事の
能力のﾊﾞﾗﾝｽがおかしい！
そのﾂﾗ どう考えても
仕事のできるﾔﾂのﾂﾗだろう！
You act like you can easily handle all of your cases!
なのに どうして 全然ﾀﾞﾒなの？
なんで ﾑﾀﾞにﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ!?
But why are you so useless? Why is your hard-boiled so pointless?
《他人から見れば
ﾑﾀﾞに見えるこだわり｡
Some things may seem useless to some people...
しかし
そこに 男のすべてがある》
But that's all about men care about.
(上司)うるせえんだよ！
存在そのものが ﾑﾀﾞなﾔﾂが言うな！
Shut up! I don't want to hear that from someone so useless!
おい！ 葉巻やめろ それ！
Hey, stop smoking that cigar!
なんで
上司から説教されてんのに➡
How can you smoke a cigar while your boss lectures you?!
葉巻ふかしてんだよ！
ぶっとばすぞ!!
I'm going to kick you out!
平次… ﾃﾒｴが あらぬところで
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲってる間に➡
Heiji while you were off acting hard-boiled somewhere there was another victim.
また 犠牲者が出たんだぜ！
ん？ まさか また狐が…？
Don't tell me...that fox again?
(上司)ああ まただよ｡
忍び入った店の者｡
Right, it was him again.
He snuck into the shop and did everyone in, from the owner to the workers.
店主から丁稚に至るまで
１人残らずだ｡
もう 狐のやつは
ただの凶族になりさがっちまった｡
That fox became a wicked man.
平次 こいつぁ 10年も
ﾔﾂを追っていながら➡
And you Heiji have been chasing him for ten years and still can't capture him.
一度も捕まえられなかった
ﾃﾒｴの罪だ！
It's all your fault.
ﾃﾒｴが ﾔﾂを捕まえてりゃ
犠牲者も出なかった｡
If you had caught him, there wouldn't have been any more victims.
ﾃﾒｴが ﾔﾂを捕まえてりゃ➡
If you had caught him, the fox wouldn't have turned so bad.
狐も あそこまで
堕ちることはなかった！
ﾃﾒｴは 立派な罪人だ｡
You're the real criminal! I should arrest you for being so useless.
無能というのも
罪目に加えてえもんだね｡
♪♪～
You were suspended. Well, we're sorry.
(新八)自宅謹慎…
なんか すいませんね｡
ﾎﾞｸらが
呼び込みなんてかけたせいで➡
It's because we invited you into our shop and put you in that situation.
こんなことになっちゃって｡
でも そっちはそっちで➡
But you also made the mistake of thinking that we were criminals.
ﾎﾞｸらを犯人と勘違いして
引き立てていったんだから➡
おあいこですよね｡
こっちも仕事ですから｡
So I guess we're even now. We did our job, anyway.
万事屋か…
金さえもらえば 何でもやる…｡
The Odd Jobs... You'll do anything as long as you get paid...
It's a job far from those who are hard-boiled.
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞとは 縁遠い職業だな｡
なに？ さりげなく見下してる？
What? Do you really look down on us that much?
ﾌｯ… まったく ｵﾚとしたことが｡
I can't believe I'd...
《落ち込みはしない…
いつものことだ｡
I'm not depressed. It happens all the time. So many things happen in life.
人生は さまざまなことが起こる》
♪♪～
It doesn't matter if good things... or bad things happen.
Either way, I have a glass of Camus... Nothing changes my day.
Camus... The man's...
もういい うぜえ！
That's enough. It's so annoying.
うわぁ～っ ちょっと！
なにするんだ ｷｻﾏ!!
What did you do, bastard?! My hard-boiled...!
ｵﾚの ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞを！
もういい しつこい ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ｡
That's enough. You repetitive hard-headed fool.
しつこい ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞって
しかたないだろ！
Hard-headed?! It can't be helped since it's hard-boiled!
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞなんだから！
そんななぁ ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞで
頭いっぱいで➡
Your brain is so full of hard-boiled nonsense you can't work.
仕事も手につかないならなぁ！
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞなんて やめちまえ！
この ﾊﾞｶﾁﾝが!!
So quit being so hard-boiled! You idiot!
お母さん!?
Mother?!
That way, both you and hard-boiled will be happy!
(神楽)そのほうが
お前にとっても➡
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞにとっても 幸せだわ！
んんっ… できるもん！
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞも仕事も！
No, no! I can handle it! I can have it both ways, hard boiled and working.
ｵﾚ 両立するもん！
Well, you already failed at being both hard-boiled and hard working...
いや
もう両方 成り立ってませんよ｡
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞも仕事も…｡
(親父)ﾀﾞﾝﾅ…
そのへんに しとかにゃ➡
Sir...
...you'd better stop now, or your wife will get upset again.
また奥さんに どやされますぜ｡
《家庭に仕事の愚痴は
持ち込まない…｡
Don't bring complaints about work back home. That's how a man acts.
それが 男の作法だ》
(神楽)また やってるよ｡
He's doing it again.
You have to be cool in front of your wife.
《妻の前では
いつも 身奇麗でいる｡
それが 夫婦円満のｺﾂ…｡
That's the key to couples living in harmony.
That's why I'm having Camus today to rejuvenate myself.
だから 今日もｵﾚは こうして
ｶﾐｭで身を清めるのだ》
ｺｲﾂ ｶﾐｭって言いてえだけだよ｡
This guy just wants to say "Camus" all the time.
ｶﾐｭって言えば
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞになると思ってるよ｡
He thinks he's hard-boiled whenever he says "Camus."
っていうか ｺｲﾂに
家庭があるってのが驚きｱﾙよ｡
All things aside, I'm surprised that he even has a family.
人間 見た目じゃないって
言いますからね｡
It's said that you can't judge people by their appearance.
いや それ逆だろ…｡
No, it's the opposite. In this guy's case, he's messed up inside.
このｵｯｻﾝ 中身は もっと
ｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞだから｡
Even though I didn't say a word, it broke my heart... Camus...
《口には出さないが
結構 傷つくｶﾐｭ》
普通に口で言えよ！
Speak normally!
Sometimes you can make your wife happy just by sharing your problems and listening
たまには 女房に愚痴こぼして
話 聞いて➡
花 もたしてやんのも
夫婦円満のｺﾂですよ｡
to what she has to say. That's the way couples stay in harmony.
どうせ また 狐に
逃げられたんでしょ｡
I bet you failed to capture the fox again, right?
ﾌﾝｯ…｡
Humph.
Really, this master is too wise for me.
《まったく このﾏｽﾀｰには
かなわない｡
なんでも ｵﾚのことはお見通し｡
He already knew so much about me.
思えば 10年来のつきあいｶﾐｭ…》
Think about it, we've known each other for over 10 years, Camus.
また ｶﾐｭって言った！
ﾑﾘﾔﾘ ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞにしたよ！
He said "Camus" again. He's really pushing himself to be hard-boiled.
《小銭形:もう 本当の
親父のようなものだな｡
It's like he's my real dad. I guess he probably feels the same, too.
向こうも 恐らく
そう思っているだろう》
(親父)思ってねえよ｡
《くたばれｼﾞｼﾞｲｶﾐｭ》
No, I don't.
Drop dead old man. Camus.
もはや ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞでも
なんでもないよ｡
He can't be considered hard-boiled anymore.
そういや 狐の野郎が
江戸に最初に現れたのも➡
By the way, the fox made his first appearance in Edo about ten years ago.
10年ほど前… いやはや➡
Well, you've been trying to capture him since then.
あれから ずっと
ﾔﾂを追いかけてなさるとは…｡
あっしは 10年間も 愚痴を
聞かされ続けたってわけですな｡
That means I've been hearing your complaints for ten years.
(親父)狐の野郎も あれから
ずいぶんと変わっちまいましたね｡
The fox has changed a lot over the years, too.
神出鬼没の伝説の盗賊
狐火の長五郎｡
The elusive criminal and legendary thief-Chogoro the Foxfire.
人を殺さず 貧しき者から盗まず➡
There was a time when he didn't kill,
悪党から金を巻き上げ
貧しき民にばらまく➡
just stealing riches and giving them to the poor so that he could earn respect.
義賊なんて もてはやされた
時代もありましたが…｡
However, he became a wicked man who stole anything and killed anyone.
いまや 殺し 押し込み
何でもやる凶賊に➡
成り果てちまった… まぁ
もともと 盗人なんてやって➡
But he used to be a thief, so he wasn't really a good guy anyways.
ﾛｸなﾔﾂじゃなかったんでしょうが｡
...He's not like that.
(小銭形)ﾔﾂは違う｡
I'm pretty surprised I actually said something like that on the fly.
《思わず そう口走った自分に➡
内心 驚きを隠せなかった》
You liar! You look pretty calm.
ｳｿつけよ 冷静じゃねえか｡
《盗人… それも
10年 追いかけ続けた敵の➡
The thief... I can't believe I'm supporting the enemy I've been chasing for over ten years, Camus.
肩をもつとはｶﾐｭ…｡
But as his enemy... or as his rival... we've had so many fights.
だが 敵として… ﾗｲﾊﾞﾙとして➡
何度も 相対した ｵﾚだからこそ➡
見えるものがある…｡
That's why I can see something like this.
Men are creatures who understand each other only after fighting it out with their fists.
男ってﾔﾂは いつだって
殴りあわなきゃ➡
わかりあえない生き物らしい…》
What kind of flashback is that? It's not even fighting!
何の回想だ？ 殴り合ってねえよ！
It's so one-sided, with you taking all the hits. That's your wish?!
一方的に殴られてるよ！
これ お前の願望じゃねえか!!
あれは… ｵﾚの知ってる
狐じゃない｡
That was...not the fox I knew...
ﾃﾒｴのﾙｰﾙも
持ち合わせていない野郎は➡
A guy who doesn't live by his own rules is useless, regardless of whether he's good or bad.
悪事だろうが 善事だろうが
何やったって ﾀﾞﾒなのさ｡
(神楽)ﾀﾞﾒなのは ｵﾒｴだよ｡
You're the useless one.
(小銭形)悪人か善人かは
知らんが➡
I don't know if he's bad or good, but the fox I knew at least lived by his own rules.
少なくとも ｵﾚの知っている狐は➡
自分の流儀は 持ち合わせていた｡
盗み入った屋敷に
食いかけのお揚げと書き置きを➡
[Thanks for the food.]
He's like a mischievous guy who sneaks into a house, leaving a piece of fried tofu and a thank-you note.
必ず残していくような…｡
Although he was a thief, he had a sense of humor. He was really cool.
泥棒のくせに 茶目っ気があって
どこか 粋なﾔﾂだった｡
そんなﾔﾂが 殺しなんぞ…｡
There's no way that kind of guy would kill people.
(ﾊｼﾞ)ｱﾆｷ！
Boss!
ﾊｼﾞ！ どうした？
Haji, what's the matter?
てえへんなんです
見てくだせえ ｺｲﾂを！
Something terrible has happened! Look at this!
This is...
ｺｲﾂは…！
[MY NEXT TARGET WILL BE THE GOLDEN FRIED TOFU STATUE AT OEDO MUSEUM. TRY TO STOP ME, IF YOU CAN. TO THE BAKUFU GOVERNMENT.]
[Note: In Japanese mythology, fried tofu is a favorite food of the fox.]
(小銭形)犯行予告状！
...A letter foretelling a crime?!
今晩 狐が盗みに入った屋敷に…｡
完全にﾅﾒられてやす！
This was found in a house the fox snuck into tonight.
He completely underestimated us.
こんなもん ﾊﾞﾗまかれて
取り逃がした日にゃ ｱﾁｷら…｡
If we can't catch him after he distributes a message like this, we'll...
(小銭形)おのれ～！
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞなﾏﾈを～!!
That bastard! How could he do something so hard-boiled?!
Wait.
待てよ！
Are you certain you want to violate your suspension just to clear your enemy's name?
謹慎まで破って わざわざ
敵の汚名を晴らそうってのか？
It's not something like that.
(小銭形)そんなんじゃない…｡
ただ… ｵﾚにも
ｵﾚの流儀があるだけだ｡
I just...I just have my own style.
I'll destroy that rotten egg with my jutte!
腐った卵は
ｵﾚの十手で ぶっ潰す！
それが ｵﾚのﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙ道だ！
That's my way of being hard-boiled!
(親父)旦那… 勘定まだです｡
Sir, you didn't pay the bill yet.
(小銭形)あっ すんません…｡
Oh, sorry about that.
ｲﾏｲﾁ ｷﾏらない人だなぁ｡
He's not very cool.
しかも全部
小銭で払ってるんですけど｡
And he's using only small change to pay.
どんなﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ…｡
What kind of hard-boiled person is he?
もう戻ってこねえかも
しれねえんで➡
In case you don't return, I charged all your bills.
今までのﾂｹの分も…｡
親父がﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞだよ 渇いてるよ!!
Hey, old man, you're really hard-boiled! He's so callous.
ｸﾞｯﾅｲ！ ﾏｽﾀｰ…｡
Good night, Master.
だから ﾏｽﾀｰじゃねえ！
I told you not to call me master.
うん… ほい！
Well... Then I'll give all of these to you, sir.
じゃあ ｺｲﾂは そのまま旦那へ｡
あぁ？ 何だよ これ！ 親父｡
Ah, what's this, old geezer?
旦那たちは さっき➡
Sir, you just said you're an Odd Jobs man and that you'll do anything.
何でもやる万事屋だと
おっしゃってやしたね｡
さっきも言ったとおり
ﾜｼも 10年もの間➡
I already told you that I've been hearing that man's complaints for ten years.
そこの旦那に
愚痴 聞かされててねえ｡
やれ 狐だ 狸だって…｡
A fox or a racoon...
(小銭形)ん？
もう うんざりでね
聞きたかねえんですよ｡
I'm getting sick of it. I'd rather not hear it anymore. I just want him to finish it.
さっさと
ｹﾘつけてもらいたくてね｡
(親父)どうぞ 小銭形の旦那を
よろしくお願いしまさぁ｡
Please help, Mr. Kozenigata.
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ～！
Hard-boiled! It's the real thing!
ﾊﾝﾊﾟじゃねえよ！
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞの化身だよ!!
He's the embodiment of hard-boiled!
もう やってらんねえよ！
ﾏｽﾀｰが いちばんﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞじゃん!!
I can't stand this anymore! Master is the best hard-boiled man, after all!
(親父)ﾏｽﾀｰじゃねえ！
親父ですよ 旦那｡
Don't call me master, I'm just an old man.
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ～！
やっぱ 親父 ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ!!
Hard-boiled?! You're hard-boiled! Was that hard-boiled?
今の ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞか!?
ってか ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ言い過ぎて➡
As I said, you're using hard-boiled too many times,
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ何なのか
わけ わかんなくなってきた～！
so I'm getting confused about what it actually means!
(銀時/神楽/新八)ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ～！
Hard-boiled!
(小銭形)ｶﾐｭ…｡
しつけえんだよ ｵﾒｴは！
...Camus.
You're really insistent!
♪♪～
すごい警備の数ですね｡
There's so much security.
(ﾊｼﾞ)そりゃそうですよ｡
Of course! Because the Magistrate's reputation is on the line.
(ﾊｼﾞ)お奉行の威信が
かかってやすからね｡
ここに忍び入って ﾔﾂらより
先に 狐 捕まえるのか…｡
We need to sneak in there and capture the fox before them.
But that'll make us look like thieves.
まるで ｵﾚたちが泥棒だな｡
心配いりやせんよ
ｱﾁｷが手引きするんで…｡
Don't worry about it. I'll guide you.
ｱﾁｷら目明しってのは
その多くが➡
Most undercover agent teams consist of ex-convicts.
軽い罪を犯した者で
構成されてるんです｡
泥棒 捕まえるには
泥棒ってやつです｡
You need a thief to catch a thief.
かくいうｱﾁｷも 昔は…｡
And that is what I used to be.
だから こういうの得意なんです｡
So, I'm really good at this stuff.
心配 直撃なんですけど！
That's what I'm so worried about!
Somebody get this kid outta here!
誰か この子 連れてって!!
Hey, don't make so much noise!
(小銭形)おい 大きな声を出すな！
What are we going to do if the security guards discover us?
警備に気づかれたら
どうするんだ！
お前が どうするんだ～！
What are you doing?!
At a time like this, you should give up being hard-boiled!
こんなときくらい
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞ脱ぎ捨ててこい！
ﾊﾞｶなのか！ お前は ﾊﾞｶなのか!?
Are you an idiot? Really an idiot?
ﾊﾞｶ野郎！
このﾊﾞｲｸは落ちてたんだよ!!
Idiot! This bike was abandoned.
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞのﾔﾂの前には
ﾊﾞｲｸが落ちてるもんなんだ！
A hard-boiled man always encounters a hard-boiled bike.
｢あぶ刑事｣でも ﾀｶが
よく 落ちてるﾊﾞｲｸ乗って➡
In Abunai Deka, Taka always picks up an abandoned bike on the street and chases the criminals, you know.
[Note: Taka is from the detective drama TV series, Abunai Deka (Dangerous Cops).]
敵を追跡したろ！
Well, Taka is sort of hard-boiled...
(小銭形)まぁ ｱｲﾂも
結構ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞだからな！
You're seriously deranged!
ｱﾝﾀは ﾏｼﾞで危ないから
ﾏｼﾞで危ないから どいて！
This is really dangerous so get out of the way!
みんな
｢近寄らないでぇ刑事｣だから！
Everyone stay away from this detective!
(小銭形)わかったよ
降りりゃいいんだろ 降りりゃ｡
All right. I have to get off, right?
Hey! I'm getting tired of pointing that out!
おい！
もうﾂｯこむの めんどくせえよ!!
ｵﾒｴは どんだけ
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞで武装してんだ！
How much hard-boiled equipment are you carrying?
なんで ﾊﾞｽﾛｰﾌﾞなんだ！
Why are you in a bathrobe?!
You look like a hard-boiled man who is done for the day!
お前 それはもう ひと仕事
終えたあとのﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞだろ！
(小銭形)ﾀｶが 仕事場 行くときも
ﾊﾞｽﾛｰﾌﾞって言ってたから｡
Taka said that he wears a bathrobe to work.
[Note: Kagura is singing "Cat's Eye" by Anri in the background.]
ｵﾒｴ 何やかんやで ちょっと
ﾀｶに憧れてんじゃねえかよ！
You! Whatever. Stop trying to be like Taka!
いいから とりあえず それ 脱げ！
Geez, take it off.
えっ 脱ぐの？
いいから脱げっつってんだよ｡
Huh? Take this off?
Just take it off. It pisses me off when I see it.
腹立つんだよ!!
なんか それ見てたら！
全身ﾀｲﾂに着替えろ！
Change into tights.
いや ﾀｲﾂは勘弁してください
もっこりしちゃうじゃないですか｡
No, tights won't do. They'll bulge.
いいんだよ！
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｺﾌﾞﾗも着てたろうが!!
It's all right. Cobra in Space Cobra wore them and he bulged, too.
[Note: Space Cobra is a TV anime based on the Cobra manga in JUMP.]
もっこりしてたろうが！
でも どこで着替えれば…
う～ん こんなところじゃ…｡
But where can I change?
Um... This kind of place doesn't look very...
どこの箱入り娘？ 男だろ!!
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞなんじゃなかったの!?
What are you, a little girl?!
You're a man, aren't you?!
Aren't you a hard-boiled man?!
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞだからこそ
必要な こだわりがある｡
Because I'm hard-boiled, I have to struggle to do the right thing.
As a hard-boiled man, I can't change like mere kids...
ﾊｰﾄﾞﾎﾞｲﾙﾄﾞともあろうものが
そこら辺の子供みたいに…｡
だから それ もうよせって
言ってんだろうが！
I already told you to stop doing that! That's enough!
しつけえんだよ！ おい神楽…｡
Hey, Kagura, give him another one. You...
それ もう１着 貸せ！
お前 持って…｡
Here I come!
あ～れ～！
The suspect! There's the suspect!
(同心)くせ者！ くせ者だ～!!
♪♪～
Good, the diversion plan worked like a charm.
よし 陽動作戦 成功だ｡
ｳｿつけ～！
You liar!
今のうちに 裏から侵入するぞ！
Use this opportunity to sneak in from the back.
神楽の死をﾑﾀﾞにするな！
Don't let Kagura's death go to waste!
♪♪～
[Preview]
The next episode...
Hey, what about Part B?! Didn't the eyecatch just air?!
We'll see you next week!
It's because you took up all that time before Part A!
The next episode... "Hard-Boiled Eggs Don't Crack," Camus.
♪♪～
(小銭形)さて次回は…｡
おい Ｂﾊﾟｰﾄ どうした！
今 ｱｲｷｬｯﾁ 入ってたろ？
ﾌｯ… お楽しみは また来週だ｡
っつうか お前が ｱﾊﾞﾝで
ﾀﾞﾗﾀﾞﾗやってたからじゃねえか！
Mitsumeru Cat's eye
Magic play is dancing.
Midori iro ni hikaru
Mitsumeru Cat's eye
Magic play is dancing...
[Chogoro the Foxfire's next target is the Golden Fried Tofu Statue.]
[Will Kozenigata be able to capture him? And... What's the pair's fateful past?]